

Port Moody, BC, Canada

□ (+1) 250-715-6128 | mike@chester.io | chester.io | mchestr | in mchestr

Summary

Senior full stack developer with 8+ years of complete software development lifecycle. My practical experience includes infrastructure automation, backend/frontend software development on highly scalable systems, application security, operational support, testing, and people management. I strive to keep up to date with the latest technologies and best practises and try to incorporate them wherever feasible.

Experience _____

Amazon Web Services

Vancouver BC, Canada

April 2020 - Present

Feb 2018 - April 2020

Aug 2016 - Feb 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

- Developer on the AWS Commerce Platform
- Technologies: Java, AWS

Idemia Vancouver BC, Canada

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Project lead and backend Python developer working on core eSIM/SIM orchestration product
- · Built highly available and distributed systems to asynchronously provision eSIM/SIM use cases from the ground up
- · Responsible for communicating, designing, developing, and delivering multiple client projects from start to finish
- Built DevOps tooling to troubleshoot problems in eSIM/SIM provisioning
- Technologies: Python, Go, Clojure, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Salt Stack, AWS

CA Technologies Vancouver BC, Canada

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Full stack Java developer on the API Management Portal product
- Responsible for designing, implementing, and testing real time API provisioning on remote API gateways
- · Mentored employees on Python scripting and git best practices
- Built Python scripts to on-board new and existing customers
- Leader for an internal API first group, to help guide teams to develop APIs following best practises
- Technologies: Java, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, OpenShift, TeamCity

Siaras Burnaby BC, Canada

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May 2014 - Aug 2016

Sept. 2009 - May 2014

arXiv: 1311.0058

- Core Python developer working on the Siaras cloudScape/cloudBurst product
- · Involved in designing, documenting, implementing, and testing custom plugins for OpenStack
- · Developed solutions for abstracting different cloud technologies into a single common OpenStack API layer
- Helped design and develop creative WAN solutions using a variety of technologies such as GRE, VPN, and L2 Gateway
- Implemented end-to-end tests which integrate into our CI/CD infrastructure
- Technologies: Python, MongoDB, OpenStack

Education

University of Victoria BC, Canada

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Publications and Awards

Dynamic web cache publishing for IaaS clouds using Shoal, Ian Gable, Michael Chester, Patrick

2013 Armstrong, Frank Berghaus, Andre Charbonneau, Colin Leavett-Brown, Michael Paterson, Robert Prior, Randall Sobie and Ryan Taylor

2013 Undergraduate Student Research Award, NSERC

References _____

Available Upon Request

May 3, 2022 Mike Chester · Resume 1